<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tim &amp; Data Science</title>
    <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tim &amp; Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 22:48:12 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 4</title>
      <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 22:48:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-4/</guid>
      <description>Today, I focused on getting some good ol&#39; SQL practice in. I solved 4 SQL problems, one of which was a LeetCode hard.
My learnings from doing those problems were: when to use RANK() vs DENSE_RANK(), that JOINs accept expressions and not something fancy, so you can join on ANDs and ORs and inequalities.
I&amp;rsquo;m also slowly figuring out my patterns. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a break tomorrow and focus on meta-learning and getting my processes in place for how to approach things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3</title>
      <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 21:44:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-3/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a phone screen with a recruiter today. It went well enough that they want me to talk to the hiring manager next week. So fingers crossed on that!
I wanted to build something a little more visual today, so I spent half an hour using Plotly Dash to build out COVID-19 Vaccine Delivery Map. I posted it on LinkedIn with a screenshot, so hopefully it will catch some people&amp;rsquo;s attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2</title>
      <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 22:14:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting in extra time into work the past couple days and it&amp;rsquo;s starting to show in how I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to study and put in time into my projects.
I did 3 SQL Leetcode questions. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get more comfortable working on SQL questions as I know that&amp;rsquo;s one of my weaker points. My goal is to be able to pull away and learn one thing from every Leetcode question that I attempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1</title>
      <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 20:51:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-1/</guid>
      <description>Today was also a light day. I was primarily focused on work, so therefore I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to do much studying. I reviewed some SQL interview questions as that&amp;rsquo;s probably one of my weaker points.
I was supposed to have an interview on this interviewing platform called Pramp, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get paired up with anyone today.
Has anyone heard of the platform called SharpestMinds? It&amp;rsquo;s a website that pairs you up with coaches and mentors in data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#66 Days of Data - Day 0</title>
      <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 23:18:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-0/</guid>
      <description>Today was a light day. I did a bunch of reading for grad school. For context, while working I&amp;rsquo;m pursuing a Master&amp;rsquo;s in Health Data Science from the University of Denver. One of the huge perks that I&amp;rsquo;m finding consistently throughout the program is that not only am I learn a lot about data science, but also everything ties in to healthcare in some way.
Readings The readings that I focused on today was a literature review of how data mining can be used in healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#66 Days of Data - Day -1</title>
      <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-negative-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 22:26:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/day-negative-1/</guid>
      <description>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s intentially a -1.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a journey of #66DaysOfData for the past 20 or so days. The original concept of this is to dedicate at least 5 minutes a day learning or working towards something data science-related.
Some people would think I had misread it because I&amp;rsquo;ve been pouring in close to 5 hours a day on this for the past few weeks.
This is my chronicle of things I&amp;rsquo;ve done to work towards becoming a data scientist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 22:19:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, My name is Tim! I am a software-engineer-turned-data-scientist that is looking to leap into data science within the healthcare space.
Throughout my time in industry and in college, I have always been fascinated by data and have worked with it extensively. In college, I performed exploratory data analysis on topics such as classic sitcoms to how to maximize your bang for your buck at Chipotle.
At my first job out of college at IBM, I worked extensively on a product that visualized KPIs and customer paths for marketing analysts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 22:19:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tacastillo.github.io/blog/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, My name is Tim! I am a software-engineer-turned-data-scientist that is looking to leap into data science within the healthcare space.
Throughout my time in industry and in college, I have always been fascinated by data and have worked with it extensively. In college, I performed exploratory data analysis on topics such as classic sitcoms to how to maximize your bang for your buck at Chipotle.
At my first job out of college at IBM, I worked extensively on a product that visualized KPIs and customer paths for marketing analysts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
